<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<content>
	<Cont id ="1">
		<type>v</type>
	</Cont>
	<Cont id ="2">
		<screentitle>Module Summary</screentitle>
	</Cont>
	<Cont id ="3">
		<pageNo>31 of 31</pageNo>
	</Cont>
	<Cont id ="4">
		<ost><![CDATA[
		<p class='body'>In this module,<b><span class='hyperlink'>Decision-making and Iterations,</span></b>you learnt about:<br></p>
		<p class='body'><img src='images/bullet.jpg' vspace ='1'>Decision-making statements<br> </p>
		<p class='body'><img src='images/bullet.jpg' vspace ='1'>Loops<br></p>
		<p class='body'><img src='images/bullet.jpg' vspace ='1'>Jump statements<br></p>
		<p class='instruction'>Click on each link for a summary of the lesson.</p>
				
				]]></ost>
		</Cont>
	<Cont id ="5">
		<img>./jm_c01_t01/imagedata/jm_c01_t01_p34.swf</img>
	</Cont>
	<Cont id ="6">
		<audioText></audioText>
	</Cont>
	<Cont id ="7">
		<knowMore>
		<b>Decision-Making statements</b>

			The decision-making statements in Java allow us to control the flow of program execution based upon certain conditions. The if statement tells your program to execute a certain section of code only if a particular test evaluates to true. The if-else statement also provides a secondary path of execution when an "if" clause evaluates to false. Unlike if and if-else, the switch statement allows for any number of possible execution paths. 

		<b>Loops</b>

			Loops allow you to execute a block of statements repeatedly. Java uses three types of loop statements: while, do-while and for. The while statement executes a block of statements as long as the condition is true. The do-while statement executes a block of statements at least once and then keeps going as long as a condition is true. The for statement executes a block of statements for a specified number of times.

		<b>Jump statements</b>

			Jump statements unconditionally transfer control to another point within the program. The break statement exits to the nearest enclosing switch, while, do-while and for statements. The continue statement starts a new iteration of the outer while, do-while or for statements. The frequent use of break and continue statements are not advisable in programming

		</knowMore>
	</Cont>
 </content>