<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android">
<!--
**************************************************  
* regular_activity_prompt
**************************************************  
-->
    <string name="regular_activity_prompt">
    This is a sample application to test how QSB and Search Key
    interacts with activities. This application has 4 activities
    including this one. The activity you are looking at is 
    called a Regular Activity and is one of 4. The other three
    you can access through the menu.
    \n\n
    This activity is a regular activity that is unaware of 
    any search capabilities. If you click search key now
    it will NOT invoke the global search by default. You can
    override onSearchRequested() to enable global search.
    \n
    \nThe other activities demonstrate:`
    \n\n1) No search Activity: An activity that disables search
    \n2) Invoke search: programatically invoke global search
    \n3) Local Search Activity: Invoke Local Search
    \n
    \nYour debug will appear here
    </string>
    
<!--
**************************************************  
* no_search_activity_prompt
**************************************************  
-->
    <string name="no_search_activity_prompt">
    In this activity the onSearchRequested
    returns a false. The search button
    should be ignored now.
    \n
    \nYou can click back now to access the 
    previous activity and use the menus again
    to choose other activities.
    </string>
<!--
**************************************************  
* search_activity_prompt
**************************************************  
-->
    <string name="search_activity_prompt">
This is called a search activity or search results activity. This activity
is invoked by clicking on the search key when
some other activity uses this activity as its
search results activity.
\n\n
Typically you can retrieve the query string
from the intent to see what the query is.
    </string>
<!--
**************************************************  
* search_invoker_activity_prompt
**************************************************  
-->
    <string name="search_invoker_activity_prompt">
In this activity a search menu item is used
to invoke the default search. In this case
as there is no local search for this activity
specified global search is invoked. Use the
menu button to see the "search" menu. when you
click on that search menu you will see the 
global search.
    </string>
<!--
**************************************************  
* local_search_enabled_activity_prompt
**************************************************  
-->
    <string name="local_search_enabled_activity_prompt">
This is a very simple activity that has indicated through 
the manifest file that there is a an associated search
activity. With this association when the search key is 
pressed the local search is presented instead of global.
\n\n
You can see the local nature of it by looking at the 
label of the QSB and also the hint in the QSB. Both
came from the search metadata.
\n\n
Once you click on the query icon, it will transfer
you to the local search activity.
    </string>
<!--
**************************************************  
* Other values
**************************************************  
    <string name="app_name">Sample Search Application</string>
-->
	<string name="search_label">Local Search Demo</string>
	<string name="search_hint">Local Search Demo Hint</string>
</resources>
