<Glossary>

<Item>
<Word>Amadeus</Word>
<Description>A global distribution system (GDS) that provides global communications and electronic distribution of information for travel service providers. Web site: http://www.global.amadeus.net</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>American Express@Work Reporting&#174;</Word>
<Description>This interactive on-line reporting solution covers both pre and post travel data at the core or enhanced service level. Users log-on to our secure Web site to run the reports of their choice.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>American Express&#174; DealPower</Word>
<Description>A complete end-to-end solution for managing and optimizing negotiated contracts, DealPower blends advanced technology with American Express intellectual capital and vendor relationship to provide unparalleled savings opportunities.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Apollo</Word>
<Description>The name under which the Galileo GDS is marketed in the United States. Web site: http://www.galileo.com </Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Airline Reporting Corporation (ARC)</Word>
<Description>An agency that processes all agency to airline accountable documents. Web site: http://www.arccorp.com </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Automated Ticket and Boarding Pass (ATB)</Word>
<Description>Type of printed ticket used by all US American Express offices. Originally combined the ticket and boarding pass in one document.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Auxiliary Segments</Word>
<Description>Any piece of the overall reservation in the computer that is not a flight booking, such as car or hotel. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Buffer Zone</Word>
<Description>An area 225 miles wide, extending beyond the northern and southern United States borders, where special tax provisions apply. Applicable to points in Canada and Mexico. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Circle Trip</Word>
<Description>A journey from point A to point B and back to point A, which is not via the same routing, airline or class of service in both directions.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>City Pair</Word>
<Description>The departure and stopover/destination points used to construct a flight itinerary.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Commuter Carrier</Word>
<Description>Carrier which operates only smaller equipment between cities which cannot support major aircraft or traffic usually over a small geographic area.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Computerized Reservations System (CRS)</Word>
<Description>A computer network through which travel services are booked, also referred to as GDS or Global Distribution System.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Corporate or Commercial Rate</Word>
<Description>A discount rate negotiated with a company or special customer; a special rate that is sometimes available to all business travelers. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Corporate Travel Department (CTD)</Word>
<Description>CTD designation is an accreditation that allows a corporation to obtain an ARC number. This licenses the organization to operate its own in-house travel agency without selling agency services to the public.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Corporate Travel Online (CTO)</Word>
<Description>The American Express online booking tool for large corporations was developed in partnership with GetThere Inc., a leading developer of Web-based corporate booking systems. The tool delivers an online end-to-end travel solution that dramatically reduces the cost of the travel booking and fulfillment services while providing world-class specialized support to corporate clients and their travelers. </Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Destination </Word>
<Description>The last stopping point on a passenger's itinerary. (Also referred to as the arrival city.) In the case of round trips or circle trips, the origin and destination points are the same.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Double Open Jaw </Word>
<Description>An itinerary with an open end on the outbound and return (two one ways issued on the same ticket). </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Downline</Word>
<Description>Refers to all segments (legs) of an itinerary after the originating flight.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Emergency Travel Services Gold</Word>
<Description>American Express supports travelers on the road with this world-class assistance for travelers in need. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>E-Ticket</Word>
<Description>The process of issuing a flight coupon(s) as an electronic image through the CRS.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Executive Travel and Concierge Services</Word>
<Description>This American Express service is designed to handle every detail of executives' travel needs including trip planning, proactive support on the road and ensuring customer satisfaction at the highest level.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)</Word>
<Description>The government agency which regulates civil aviation in the United States. The FAA's functions include the enforcement of airline security regulation, monitoring airport traffic control systems, monitoring aircraft maintenance, and licensing pilots. Web site: http://www2.faa.gov</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Fee Allocator</Word>
<Description>Fee Allocator is offered by American Express to drive traveler behavior towards preferred booking options, in order to reduce overall travel spending.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Galileo</Word>
<Description>A global distribution system (GDS) that provides global communications and electronic distribution of information for travel service providers. Web site: http://www.galileo.com</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Global Data Consolidation</Word>
<Description>This American Express product consolidates global travel spend from any third party agency around the world with American Express data, into our global data repository to give companies a clear picture of their overall global expenditure. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Global Distribution System (GDS)</Word>
<Description>A computer network through which travel services are booked, also known as the Computerized Reservations System (CRS).</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Global Ticket TRAX&#174;</Word>
<Description>This American Express e-ticket refund service automatically initiates the refunding of all unused refundable e-tickets that have aged according to client specifications booked through American Express. </Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Guest Name Record (GNR)</Word>
<Description>Hotel's term for a reservation record, similar to an airline's PNR (Passenger Name Record).</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Hold Time</Word>
<Description>Time when non-guaranteed hotel rooms are released back to the hotel for sale (e.g., 4 p.m. or 6 p.m.).</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>International Air Transport Association (IATA)</Word>
<Description>A voluntary membership organization which, by setting rates, establishing conditions of service, and establishing safety standards, provides a unified system of worldwide air transportation. Web site: http://www.iata.org </Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>International Airlines Travel Agent Network (IATAN) </Word>
<Description>A not-for-profit service organization whose main goal is to assist travel agents to meet and maintain a specific set of standards that are of value to airlines, the agency community, as well as to consumers. Appoints U.S. travel agents on behalf of its customer airlines. Web site: http://www.iatan.org </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Interline</Word>
<Description>The use of a connecting service which includes two or more carriers.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Interline Agreement</Word>
<Description>An agreement between carriers to transport passengers or goods.</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>International Rate Desk</Word>
<Description>American Express' International Rate Desk specializes in faring complex, multi-segment international itineraries.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Itinerary</Word>
<Description>The complete schedule of a trip.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Lowest Logical Airfare (LLA)</Word>
<Description>The lowest practical airfare within the client's designated travel policy guidelines. </Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>National Business Travel Association (NBTA) </Word>
<Description>NBTA is a professional association representing corporate travel managers and travel providers, providing its members with educational and training opportunities and vital government and media representation. Web site: http://www.NBTA.org</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Net Rate </Word>
<Description>A negotiated non-commissionable rate used by corporations or groups. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>No-Show </Word>
<Description>A guest who fails to arrive at a hotel and has not canceled the reservation within the cancellation period. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>On-Line</Word>
<Description>Connecting flights on the same carrier.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>On-Site Agency </Word>
<Description>A travel agency situated on a company's premises, doing business only for that company. </Description>
</Item>



<Item>
<Word>One-Way </Word>
<Description>A journey from an origin point A to a destination point B, either via non-stop, direct, or connection service. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Open Jaw </Word>
<Description>A circle trip in which there is a surface portion at the origin city or outward destination of the journey. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Origin </Word>
<Description>The point at which a journey commences; the beginning point. (Also referred to as the boarding point.) </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Passenger Name Record (PNR)</Word>
<Description>Any reservation held with an airline or within the Computer Reservation System (CRS). </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>PortfolioTM/Email </Word>
<Description>American Express' e-mail based reporting solution covers both pre and post travel data. Reports are automatically e-mailed to recipients on a pre-determined basis. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Profile </Word>
<Description>The record of an individual passenger's preferences kept within the Computer Reservation System (CRS). Note: The name used for these varies between reservation systems. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Rack Rate </Word>
<Description>The "published," often highest, rate for a hotel room. Many hotels now have a "rate of the day," with different rack rates for different dates throughout the year. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>ReconPower </Word>
<Description>For companies that centrally bill, ReconPower, offered by American Express, streamlines the reconciliation process by matching billing statement data with travel office data and automating the research and correction process for unmatched transactions. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Record Locator </Word>
<Description>A unique number, usually a combination of letters and numbers, assigned by the CRS for any PNR or by the airline for any flight reservation. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>RezExpress </Word>
<Description>RezExpress, a national American Express call center designed for small to midsized companies, offers efficient, centralized travel reservations and customer support at a lower cost than traditional local service. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>RezPort TD, RezPort+ and RezPort </Word>
<Description>The American Express online booking tools designed specifically for small- and medium-sized companies that allow travelers to book a complete business trip online in just a few minutes. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Sabre </Word>
<Description>A global distribution system (GDS) that provides global communications and electronic distribution of information for travel service providers. Web site: http://www.sabre.com</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Segment </Word>
<Description>Each individual flight or car/hotel reservation within the overall reservation in the computer. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Single Open Jaw </Word>
<Description>An itinerary with one open end.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>SmartAlert (sm) </Word>
<Description>This non-refundable e-ticket notification is offered by American Express.</Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Stopover </Word>
<Description>A planned break of a journey made by the passenger between point of origin and destination; stopovers usually exceed 4 hours domestically. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; Gateway </Word>
<Description>This American Express product is the next generation point-of service reservation technology. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; VPN</Word>
<Description>This American Express product provides a single, independent network to access all GDS systems as well as other alternative inventory channels. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; WebFares</Word>
<Description>This American Express product provides unparalleled access to Web fares for the traditional reservation process. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; Portal</Word>
<Description>This American Express product provides centralized access to a variety of traveler tools and related links so travelers can access and update their profile, request travel, check on the arrival or departure time for a flight, view an itinerary or invoice and obtain maps and directions in one convenient location. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; My Travel Profile </Word>
<Description>This American Express product is a powerful and innovative profile database that uses leading-edge technology to streamline the way traveler profiles are created, updated and managed. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; My Travel Plans </Word>
<Description>This American Express product provides convenient, online access to itineraries and invoices. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>TravelBahn&#174; Computer Telephony Integration </Word>
<Description>This American Express product integrates the travel counselor's desktop with the phone system. </Description>
</Item>


<Item>
<Word>Worldspan </Word>
<Description>A global distribution system (GDS) that provides global communications and electronic distribution of information for travel service providers. Web site: http://www.worldspan.com</Description>
</Item>

<Item>
<Word>Worldspan </Word>
<Description>A global distribution system (GDS) that provides global communications and electronic distribution of information for travel service providers. Web site: http://www.worldspan.com</Description>
</Item>

</Glossary>		